Hey, Yuu.
（チト）ねえ ユー
What?
（ユーリ）何？
Where are we, exactly?
（チト）ここはどこなんだろう
Dunno. It's white as far as the eye can see.
（ユーリ）
さあ 見渡す限り真っ白だね
It's almost like we're the only people in the world.
（ユーリ）まるで世界に２人しか
いないみたいだね
You sure have it easy, spouting off poetry.
（チト）詩人は気楽だな
Meanwhile, I'm desperately trying to find us
a place for us to ride out the cold...
こっちは寒さをしのげる場所を
探すのに必死だってのに…
That, or...
それとも…
（チト）うううっ…
We're actually already dead, and we're in
the pure-white world of the afterlife.
（ユーリ）
実は２人とも もう死んでいて―
真っ白な死後の世界にいる
とか…
Don't say that; it's bad luck.
縁起でもない
And stop making snowballs.
あと雪玉作るのやめろ
Aww, I was just starting to have fun!
え～ 楽しくなってきたのにい
My head feels heavy, and I'm really cold.
頭が重い
それにすごく寒い
Hey, did you know that the afterlife
is supposed to be really warm?
（ユーリ）ねえ 知ってる？
死後の世界ってあったかいんだって
If that's true, then it doesn't look like we're dead yet.
（チト）だったら私たちは
まだ死んでないみたいだな
う… うううっ…
（風の音）
Sure is cold...
（ユーリ）寒いね…
♪～
Maybe today we should turn back
Maybe tomorrow we can go even further
Girls' Last Tour
Creaking
I want to find the many happy things far away
Hope sparkling with light, moving, moving
Unending talk continues on forever
Goodbye loneliness, moving, moving
Just like solving a difficult puzzle
I'm sure we'll keep learning the things we want to learn
So with a 1, 2, 3 start walking
Today and tomorrow and yesterday are all the same
In the opposite direction the world is turning
That's right, with a 1, 2, 3 start dancing
I want to forget today and tomorrow and yesterday
So with a 1, 2, 3 start moving
I'm sure that's the a-a-a-a-answer
～♪
W-we've gotta find a place to rest soon...
（チト）そ そろそろホントに
休める場所を見つけないと
Yeah...
うん…
はっ んん！
（エンジンを吹かす音）
Yuu, wake up!
あっ ユー 起きろ
I'm not sleeping.
寝てないよ…
う… くう～ うう…
はあっ… うう…
A b-b-building...
た た 建物…
It's big.
（ユーリ）ううっ…
（チト）大きい…
ふう… ううう…
Wh-wh-what kind of building is it?
（ユーリ）
なな… 何の施設だろう…
N-no clue.
（チト）さ さあな
Let's find a way in.
入り口を… 探そ… おっ
Whew.
（ユーリ）っと…
（チト）
ハァ… ハァ… う～ ううっ…
72nd Surface
Power Plant
C-can't read it...
よ 読めないな
This facility's pretty old.
相当古い施設だ
Don't know how to get in.
入り口も分からない
Hey, look, look!
（ユーリ）ねえ 見て見て
What's up?
（チト）ん？ どうした？
Th-that pipe doesn't have any snow on it at all.
（ユーリ）あ あのパイプ
全然雪が積もってない
It's melting?
溶けてる…
I-is it hot?!
あっ 熱いのか！？
Lemme shoot it.
（ユーリ）撃ってみよう
ううう…
（チト）んん… ん…
ハァ…
（チト）ううっ…
（ユーリ）ハァ…
（チト）う…
（ユーリ）ん…
んんっ…
H-hot water!
（チト）お お湯だ…
Hot water!
お湯～
（ユーリ）ああ～
（チト）ハァ～
Wh-what should we do?
（ユーリ）ど どうする？
What do you mean? C'mon.
（チト）どうするって そりゃ…
I'm glad we found a pipe in such good condition.
具合のいい管があってよかったね～
Yeah.
うん
There we go: a bath.
（ユーリ）できた… 風呂
Let's get in.
（チト）入ろう
Bath
（チト）うううっ ハァ…
Hot!
あちっ ぐ…
（ユーリ）ハァ～
（チト）あ…
The water feels really good, Chi!
いい湯だよ ちーちゃん
Y-yeah.
う うん…
（チト）ああ… つ～ つつつ…
（ユーリ）ハァ～
（チト）ん… ああっ ああ…
（ユーリ･チト）ハァ～
Feels good...
（チト）気持ちいい…
how long has it been since we had a bath?
お風呂なんて いつぶりだろ
I think we've taken two since leaving Grandpa's.
おじいさんの所を出てから
２回は入ったっけ？
Three.
３回だよ
Huh. So this is our fourth.
そっか～ じゃあ４回目だ
（チト）ハァ～
I feel like I've been brought back to life.
ハァ～ 生き返る
This is paradise, pure paradise...
（ユーリ）極楽～ 極楽～
（湯船の中で息を吐く音）
Hey, what does "paradise" mean anyway?
ねえ “極楽”って
どういう意味？
It means the afterlife.
ああ… 死後の世界って意味だな
That's an unlucky thing to say
after we've been brought back to life.
（ユーリ）せっかく生き返ったのに
縁起でもないね
Yeah.
（チト）そうだな
（ユーリ）ハハハハハ…
（チト）フフフ…
（ユーリとチトの笑い声）
Ugh, I'm getting dizzy.
あ～ のぼせてきた
（湯船の中で息を吐く音）
Journal
（きしむ音）
The wind sure is blowing hard.
すごい吹雪だね
Yeah, huh.
うん そうだね
Glad we found a place we could stay.
宿りできる場所があってよかったね
Yeah, huh.
うん そうだね
We went into a building and
blocked the entrance with snow.
“私たちは建物に入り
入り口を雪で固めた”
We were lucky to have scrap material
we could use to help retain heat.
“保温のために役に立つ有機物の
廃材があったのは幸いだった”
Oh, add more fuel.
あ 燃料追加して
Okay, okay.
ヘイヘイ
One okay is enough.
ヘイは１回だ
Okay.
（ユーリ）ヘ～イ
Must be nice for you, Chi,
making me do all the annoying work.
ちーちゃんはいいよね
めんどくさいことは私任せで
If you don't have the brains, use your brawn.
頭が足りないやつは
体動かすんだよ
You can't even read or write.
お前 ロクに読み書きも
できないだろ
Huh.
あ～ う…
What're you writing again?
それ 何 書いてんだっけ？
It's a journal or log I've been keeping since we left.
出発してからの日記というか
日誌というか…
I explained it to you before.
前にも説明したろ
You did?
そだっけ
People like you are exactly why
we need to have a journal like this.
お前みたいなやつにこそ
こういう記録が必要なんだよ
Memories fade, so we write them down.
記憶は薄れるから
記録しておくんだよ
あ～
Memories just get in the way of living.
記憶なんて生きる邪魔だぜ
Can you remember the last time you ate?
ごはん食べたかどうかくらいは
覚えといてよ
Huh? Did we eat today?
あれ？ 今日ごはん食べたっけ？
Seriously?
食べたって ハァ…
Books are really amazing.
本ってのはすごいんだよ
Ever since they were invented thousands of years ago,
humanity has been recording things in books.
何千年も前に
古代人が発明して以来―
ずっと人類は本に記録してきたんだ
Huh.
（ユーリ）ふ～ん
It's thanks to books that we can learn about
things that happened long ago.
（チト）昔のことを
知ることができるのも―
本のおかげだしね
You've always liked books, huh, Chi.
（ユーリ）ちーちゃんは昔から
本 好きだったもんね
You read a whole lot of Grandpa's books.
おじいさんの本
たくさん読んでたし
Yeah, but we had to burn most of them.
（チト）
ほとんど燃えちゃったけどね
Excluding the couple of journals, we have...
今も持ってるのは
数冊の日記を除けば…
One, two, three... four books.
１… ２… ３… ４冊か…
Lemme see.
見せて
Sure.
KAPPA
Akutagawa
はい
ふ～ん
I wonder how many books are left in the world.
世界中探しても
もうどれだけ残ってるか…
I see.
なるほど～
The fire's getting low. Add more fuel.
あっ 火 弱くなってる
燃料追加して
Okay.
はい
We don't have much fuel left to burn.
燃やせる物も
なくなってきたなあ
よっ！
あ…
What, are we out of fuel?
何？ 廃材 もうないの？
ん…？
あっ… うわああっ！
The book!
本がっ！！
Put it out!
消せ～っ！
（ユーリ）熱っ 熱い…
Hot, hot!
ハァ ハァ ハァ ハァ…
（ユーリ）ううっ… ん？
（チト）ああああ… 「河童(かっぱ)」が…
Not Kappa...
ああ…
（ユーリ）「河童」？
Kappa?
I literally just told you books were important!
（ユーリ）うううっ…
（チト）本が大事ってこと―
話したよな さっき
Sorry, I wasn't really listening!
ごめん それは
あんまり聞いてなかった
Listen!
聞けよっ！！
ぷは～っ
くう… ん！
I said I was sorry.
悪かったって
Moron! Idiot! Garbage!
バカ！ クズ！ ゴミ！
Okay.
はい
Don't "okay" me!
“はい”じゃない
Whatever, I'm going to bed!
もういい 寝るっ！
Chi.
（ユーリ）ちーちゃん
（ユーリ）ん…
Journal
Chito
C'mon, Yuu, hurry it up.
（チト）ほら ユー 早くしろ
Chi, are you still mad at me?
ちーちゃん まだ怒ってる？
No.
（チト）別に
You definitely are.
怒ってるじゃん
あ…
Ready, go!
（チト･ユーリ）せーの！
あ…
The storm cleared up!
お～っ 晴れた
The snow sure piled up.
積もったな
What do you think, doable?
（ユーリ）ん… どう 行けそう？
Think so.
何とか…
ん？
Hey, are you still mad?
ねえ まだ怒ってる？
No.
（チト）別に
Hurry up and get on.
早く乗りなよ
Even if we lost a book, we still have the journals.
本は減っても まあ
この日記があるし
Hup.
よいしょっと
If we keep writing things in our journal,
it'll be like a book...
日記も書き連ねていけば
本のようなもの
What is this?
ん？ 何だ これ？
Hey, Yuu, you drew something in here, didn't you?
おい ユー 何か落書きしたろ
Did I?
はて？
Don't go drawing in here.
落書きすんなよ
What is this, even?
何書いてあるんだ これ…
It's your face, Chi.
ちーちゃんの顔だよ
My face doesn't look like this.
（チト）私はこんな顔じゃない
It's what you look like when you're asleep.
だって寝顔だもん
（チト）フゥ…
（エンジン音）
I wanna draw some more now.
もっと落書きしたいなあ～
We're short on paper, so don't.
（チト）紙もったいないからダメ
Aww.
（ユーリ）え～
And you wrote a letter wrong.
（チト）あと 字 間違えてるぞ
Huh?
（ユーリ）え？
I'M SOKKY
"I'M SOKKY"?
（チト）“ごぬんね”？
Think it's around here.
（チト）この辺かな
Sure is nice out, despite it all.
（ユーリ）
よく晴れてるねえ それにしても
It's been nice out for a bit now.
（チト）ここのところ晴れ続きだし
That's why I figure it's gonna be coming soon.
だから
そろそろ来るんじゃないかな
What's coming?
来るって何が？
C'mon, you can hear it.
（チト）ほら 音がする
（地響き）
（ユーリ）あ…
There it is.
（チト）お～ 来た来た
The water from the melted snow.
ほら 雪解け水が…
So that's what you meant, the snow water.
来るって雪解け水のことか…
Sure is a lot.
すごい量だね
Because it's been warm now for a few days.
（チト）数日前から
かなりあったかかったからね
It must have really filled up.
たまってたはずだよ
Why does a whole lot come out all at once?
（ユーリ）なんで一度に
たくさん出てくるんだろう？
Because the ancient city's drainage system
is still here, or something.
（チト）大昔の都市の排水機能が
残ってるせいだとか何とか…
In any case, what's important is
we get some drinking water.
とにかく大切なのは 飲み水の確保
We going down on foot?
徒歩で行くの？
Yeah, it can't get down there.
そいつが降りられないからね
Hup.
（ユーリ）よっこら
（チト）それと…
That, and...
♪～
Gotta take our shoes off.
靴を脱がなきゃ
（ユーリ）んしょ
（チト）う… うううっ…
Cold!
冷たっ うう…
So cold!
冷た～ うっ…
（チト･ユーリ）ううう…
It's so blue, Chi.
（ユーリ）
全部真っ青だね ちーちゃん
It's like we're in the sky.
空にいるみたいだよ
Watch your step.
（チト）足元 気をつけろよ
The water might've washed down something sharp.
とがった物が
流れてきてるかもしれない
Let's look up while we walk, Chi.
（ユーリ）
上を向いて歩こうよ ちーちゃん
Look up!
上をさ
I just told you to watch where you step.
足元に気をつけろって
言ってんだろうが
What a waste when the sky's so blue!
もったいないな～
こんなに空が青いのに～
（チト）ん…
When the sky's so blue,
こんなに空が青いし…
it's good weather for a laundry day.
今日は洗濯日和だな
Laundry
Cold!
（チト）寒っ
What's this rope for?
このヒモは何？
We could get hurt if we get washed away by a current.
流されたら危ないだろ
深い所もあるし
The water gets deep in places, too.
Are you gonna take off your helmet?
ヘルメット取ったら？
I could get hurt if I fell.
転んだら危ないだろうが
Half-naked with a helmet...
半裸ヘルメット…
Our clothes sure are pretty dirty.
やっぱり結構 汚れてるなあ…
Why is the sky blue?
空って なんで青いんだろうねえ
Hey, Yuu, why're you acting so laid back?
おい ユー
なんでまったりしてんだ？
I got the water.
水なら くんだが
You gotta wash your clothes, too.
お前も服を洗うんだよ
Seriously?
マジか
Hey, Chi, why is the sky blue?
（ユーリ）ねえ ちーちゃん
空ってなんで青いの？
People long ago said it was
reflecting the blue of the ocean.
（チト）昔の人は海の青が
映っているからなんて言ってたり
The ocean?
（ユーリ）海？
It's a place with water that's way bigger
and way deeper than this puddle.
（チト）この水たまりよりも
ず～っと広く深く水がある場所だよ
The water under our feet would go on forever.
私たちの足元のず～っと下に
まだ あるとか ないとか…
I heard people long ago lived by the ocean.
昔の人は海のそばで
暮らしてたらしいけど
Hey, look, look, Chi!
（ユーリ）
あっ 見て見て ちーちゃん！
I told you to listen to-
だから聞けよっ
Hey! You idiot, don't start running all of a sudden!
…って わっ バカ！ 急に走るなっ
うっ うわああっ！
（転ぶ音）
I'm glad I was wearing my helmet.
ヘルメットかぶっててよかった…
C'mon, look, look!
（ユーリ）ねえ 見て見て
（チト）ん！
Why are you all wet, too?
なんでユーも濡れてんだ？
I fell.
コケた
Forget that, look at this!
それより見てっ これを
It's... a fish.
（チト）これは… 魚だな
Fish...
（ユーリ）魚？
Looks like it's dead though.
死んでるみたいだが
What's a fish?
魚って何なの？
It's a living thing that lives in water.
水の中に住む生き物だよ
I heard there were a lot of them in the ocean long ago.
昔は海とかに たくさんいたらしい
I thought humans were the only
living things still out there...
人以外の生き物なんて
もう生き残ってないと思ってたけど
Okay, let's eat it!
よし 食べよう
What? Can we eat it?
え～ 食べられるかな ん～
I heard people ate fish long ago,
but is this one okay?
昔の人は食べてたらしいけど…
大丈夫かな
It doesn't look like it's started to decompose...
分解は始まってないみたいだけど
う～ん
Well, maybe we can eat it if we roast it.
まあ 焼けば食べられるかな
Let's roast it!
焼こう
After we hang up our clothes to dry.
（チト）洗った物 干してからね
う…
Hey, I wonder what it feels like to live in the water.
（ユーリ）ねえ―
水の中に住むってさ
どんな感じだろうね
Dunno. Probably floating, and sinking...
さあ 浮いたり沈んだり…
I heard they flap these fins to move forward.
ここのヒレをパタパタさせて
進むらしいけど
Fins...
ヒレ？
Maybe it swam like that.
あんな感じで泳いでたのかな
Maybe.
そうかもね
Should be done by now.
そろそろ焼けたかな
Let's eat it!
（ユーリ）食べるっ！
Be careful, it's hot.
熱いから気をつけろよ
All right!
おっ おっ やった！ あちっ！
Hot!
あ…
は～むっ
ん… ん… ん… ん～
H-how is it?
ど どう？
ん… ん？ ん… ん～
ん… んん んん～
It's good!
うまい！
Let me try.
私も
Don't eat all of it!
あんまり食べないでよ
はむっ
I've never tasted anything like it.
初めて食べる味だ
It's weird.
変な味
はむっ
Me! I'm next!
（ユーリ）次！ 次 私
はむっ ん… ん…
Our clothes are all clean now.
キレイになったね 服
And these bones must feel refreshed
with all the meat cleaned off them.
こっちは肉が落ちて
すっきりしたね 骨
Refreshed, huh...
すっきりって
But where did it come in from?
でも どこから
流れてきたんだろうね
It must have come in from a higher level, huh...
（チト）
やっぱり上層からじゃないかな？
排水に混じって
Maybe if we go up higher,
we'll find a whole bunch of them.
（ユーリ）上のほうへ行けば
いっぱいいるのかな
And what if we do?
（チト）いたらどうするの？
We eat them.
（ユーリ）食べる
Eat them, huh...
（チト）食べるか
Yeah.
（ユーリ）うん
（チト）そうだな
（チト･ユーリ）ハァ～ ん～
（２人の寝息）
♪～
It's not over till it's over
Where is this place I just woke up?
What's going to start now?
Before I realized it I'm getting ready to travel with you
Let's go to a paradise sparkling in black and white (let's go)
Let's make, let's make
C'mon, let's make a world for you and me
Let's start, let's start
What should we start with? (huh?!)
Let's dance, let's dance
Let's be happy and dance! (yay, yay!)
Our last trip is beginning (beginning)
The world made up of just the two of us
Is still spinning today (around and around)
Today and tomorrow and the day after that
Can I stay by your side?
Please
Not over yet, not over yet... (Travel)
Not over yet, not over yet... (Journey)
Not over yet, not over yet... (One more time!)
Not over yet, not over yet... (Yes!)
Journey
Farewell.
さらば
Bye bye!
バイバ～イ